Finding Aid for Fred H. DeLano papers,1907-1923 and 1949-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Fred H. DeLano papers 1907-1923 and 1949-1987
DeLano, Fred H., 1916-
0.5 linear feet
921098 Aa 2
Journalist from Dowagiac, Michigan with interest in sports public relations; general manager of the Detroit Pistons.Resumes, correspondence received in 1952 in response to letter sent to college athletic directors asking the question, "What is the use of athletics for young people?"; scattered correspondence relating to his career with the Detroit Pistons; collected material about family member, Ervin Hurst; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Martha Davis (Donor No. 7964 ) in September 1991.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Fred H. DeLano was born in Dowagiac, Michigan on April 1, 1916. He attended Dowagiac High School, where he began his lifelong interest in sports by joining the Dowagiac football team. After graduating in 1933, DeLano continued this interest at the University of Michigan, where he became sports editor for the Michigan Daily, and the Ann Arbor correspondent for the Chicago Tribune. DeLano graduated in 1937 from the university with degrees in history and journalism. He embarked upon a journalism career immediately after graduation and continued writing throughout his life for many newspapers, including the Detroit Free Press and the Plymouth Observer. Beyond his journalism career, DeLano was also heavily involved with sports public relations and promotions, which landed him the position of General Manager for the Detroit Pistons, 1957-1958, the first year the team played in Detroit. Throughout his many change of positions and moves, DeLano remained involved with his home state of Michigan, his high school, college, and friends.
The Fred H. DeLano Papers contain a small amount of correspondence and publications on a wide variety of topics. The collection begins with a folder of material on Ervin Hurst, DeLano's uncle, who attended the University of Michigan (class of 1913). This one folder contains newspaper clippings about Hurst's marriage, and a leather-bound graduation program from 1913. The other files relates to Fred DeLano's activities from 1949 to 1987. Included here are copies of his resumes from 1955 to 1982, and correspondence, year books, and publications of the 50th reunions of his high school and college classes. A small portion of the material concerns DeLano's involvement with the Detroit Pistons. One set of correspondence shows the replies of about 50 college athletic directors from around the country to DeLano's question of 1952 about athletic de-emphasis, "What is the use of athletics for young people?" The collection may contain information of interest to those studying DeLano's life, sports writing, or those interested in Dowagiac High School and the University of Michigan Class of 1937.
Subjects:
Athletics--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit Pistons (Basketball team); Dowagiac (Mich.); Hurst, Ervin.; Journalists--Michigan--Dowagiac.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
DeLano, Fred H., 1916-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- DeLano papers
  - Ervin Hurst, 1907-1923 (Box 1)
  - Resumes, 1955-1982 (Box 1)
  - Tournament of Roses Parade Program, 1949 (Box 1)
    (edited by DeLano))
  - Correspondence, Athletic De-emphasis, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Pistons, Publications and Personal Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Dowagiac High School, 50th Reunion, Class of 1933, 1983 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan, 50th Reunion, Class of 1937, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Carl F. DeLano (state legislator) materials (Box 1)